# JOHNSON NGUYEN

Johnson82nguyen@gmail.com | 952-594-5175 3533 Keystone Ave Apt 2, Los Angeles, CA https://github.com/johnson82nguyen

## **OBJECTIVE**

Driven, hardworking and motivated Computer Science graduate from the University of Minnesota Twin-Cites seeking a position to promote growth and knowledge through prior experiences. Background includes over 2 years of professional experience in frontend to backend application development.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **University of Minnesota Twin-Cities**

September 2016 – May 2020

**Bachelors of Arts in Computer Science** 

Relevant coursework: Algorithms & Data Structures, Operating Systems, Program Design & Development, Machine Architecture & Org. Software Engineering 1, Databases, Internet Programming

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Skills: Python, Java, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, MYSQL, C++, C, R, PHP

Framework, Libraries, Tools: React.js, Marionette.js, Node.js, Postman, Django, GIT, Laravel, SourceTree, Bitbucket, GitHub,

Bootstrap, Docker, AWS CLI

Operating Systems: Windows 7, Windows 10, Linux, Ubuntu, Mac OS

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Full-Stack Software Engineer**

May 2021 - August 2022

Minneapolis, MN

**Modus Engagement LLC** 

- Designed and implemented front-end features in web applications used by 100+ clients such as TORO, AT&T, CATEPILLAR etc.
- Applied RESTful API methodology when building API routes with Laravel (PHP framework) for clients to input, delete and update data using MySQL.
- Worked closely with team leads (UI/UX Designer, Project manager, Lead Software engineer, CTO, QA) to retrieve requirements and deliver features efficiently and effectively in an Agile methodology.
- Discovered and updated multiple SQL queries and PHP functions by 50% for optimal runtime when dealing with thousands of user data spanning across multiple accounts.
- Updated over 80% of old UI and functionality to fit modern standards.

## **Summer Temp Instrument Builder**

June 2018 – August 2018

**Emerson Automation Solutions** 

• Focused primarily on building measurement devices. Worked with a variety of mechanical components and processes. Assembled them together following manufacturing procedures.

• Performed exceptionally well, kept workflow up-tempo and efficient.

Shakopee, MN

#### **PROJECTS**

## React.js Brewery Application

April 2021

- Worked on a final project for a company using React.js framework to connect to an existing open-source API which gathered brewery information around the United States. Allows users to search for breweries and sorts by name closest to user input.
- Built front-end React.js framework with CSS. HTML and JavaScript libraries for user friendly UI. React app is responsive for both desktop and mobile users.

#### **Node.js Website:**

January 2020 – May 2020

- Semester long project on building a website built with a HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap frontend, and a MySQL, Node.js backend.
- Used MySQL database to hold data and input from form entries and user information. The database also held information for administrators to the website such as account username and password
- The class project used a client and server side in Node.js which had an Express framework that maintained efficient web development.
- Frontend of class project done in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap allowed for eye-pleasing design and user-friendly GUI which allowed for proficient user usage

## **QUALIFICATIONS**

- 5+ years of coding experience total in the work field and as a student at the University of Minnesota Twin-cities.
- Proficient in Object Oriented Programming with Java, Python, C++, C
- Experienced in debugging code and reporting errors as well as documenting and maintaining a clear and concise codebase.
- $\bullet \ Efficient \ in \ testing \ (Google \ tests, \ regression \ tests, \ Blackbox, \ Whitebox \ testing, \ etc.)$
- Familiarity with Agile, Scrum, Waterfall software programming methodology and RESTful API.
- · Great communication skills, pro-active, task oriented and a quick learner with new technologies and concepts
- Reliable and strong team player and have the ability to work at a face pace environment and finish deliverables on time
- Apply problem solving skills in industry work, course work and in real world scenarios